-=THE LAST FANTASY=-荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：炫火飞云
校对：炫火飞云
片名：《黑天鹅》
昨晚我做了一个疯狂至极的梦
I had the craziest dream last night.
我扮演着“白天鹅”
I was dancing the White Swan.
编舞不太一样，有点像莫斯科大剧院的版本
It was different choreography, though. It was more like the Bolshoi's.
那是序幕中的一场戏
It was the prologue,
魔法师罗斯巴种下了诅咒
when Rothbart casts his spell.
粉粉的，好漂亮…
Look how pink. So pretty...
真漂亮！
Pretty!
- 你今天心情不错 - 他答应我，这一季让我演大角色
- You're in a good mood. - He promised to feature me more this season.
早该如此
Well, he certainly should.
你在团里熬了那么久
You've been there long enough,
你是最努力的舞蹈演员
and you're the most dedicated dancer in the company.
起来
Up.
- 那是什么？ - 怎么啦？
- What's that? - What?
背后
There.
没关系
Nothing.
你真不要我陪你去？
You're sure you don't want me to come with you?
乖女儿
You're a sweet girl.
你今天看见贝丝了吗？
Did you see Beth today?
她居然还有脸回来
I can't believe she's back.
- 回来很正常啊 - 不会吧，她还没看出来？
- Of course she's back. - What, she can't take a hint?
咱们团要破产了，她过气了
The company is broke. No one comes to see her anymore.
如今，能坚持看完整场芭蕾的人没有喽
Oh, nobody actually comes to see ballet full stop.
才不是呢，皇家芭蕾舞团上一季不知道有多火爆！
That's not true. I heard The Royal had one of their best seasons yet.
他得换点新花样，没别的
He just needs to try something new. That's all.
不是换新花样，得换新人
No, someone new.
- 换成谁？ - 老女人肯定不行
- Like who? - Like someone who's not approaching menopause.
真让人难过
It's sad.
难过什么？
What's sad?
贝丝多美啊！
Beth's such a beautiful dancer.
是啊，我奶奶也不丑
Yeah, so is my grandmother.
（玛格・芳廷，英国人，20世纪最优秀的芭蕾舞演员之一）
- 玛格・芳廷一直跳到了50岁 - 是，我们知道
- Well Fonteyn danced into her fifties. - Yeah, we know.
太好了
Great.
我他妈坐过了站
Thought I'd fucking missed my stop.
从79街一路狂奔过来
It's a hell-fit all the way from 79th.
跳得很好，尼娜
Beautiful as always, Nina.
放松
Relax.
一、二、三、四
And one, and two, and three, and four.
约翰，停一下
Stop, John. One second.
准备，各就各位
Okay, take position.
一、二、三、起
And one, and two, and three, and up.
一、二、三、四
And one, and two, and three, and four.
你好，亲爱的
Hello, dear.
故事情节耳熟能详
We all know the story.
纯美无暇的纤纤处子
Virginal girl, pure and sweet,
被坏人变成了一只天鹅
trapped in the body of a swan.
她渴望自由
She desires freedom
但只有真爱才能解除魔咒
that only true love can break the spell.
王子的到来，使她的愿望几乎成真
Her wish is nearly granted in the form of a Prince.
可就在，他要表白真爱之际
But before he can declare his love,
淫邪的黑天鹅，施展手段迷惑了他
The lustful twin, the Black Swan, tricks and seduces him.
白天鹅悲痛欲绝，跳崖自尽
Devastated, the White Swan leaps off a cliff,
在死亡里…
killing herself. And in death...
她得到了解脱
finds freedom.
- 早上好，团员们 - 早上好
- Good morning, company. - Good morning.
这一季的开幕戏是“天鹅湖”
We will open our season with Swan Lake.
我知道，“天鹅湖”是部老戏
Done to death, I know.
但这部不同
But not like this.
我们重新改编，使爱更真，情更切
We strip it down, make it visceral and real.
这部新作品需要一个新的天鹅女王
A new production needs a new Swan Queen.
我要向世界展示一张全新的面孔
A fresh face to present to the world.
不过…你们有谁可以同时演绎两个角色？
But... Which of you can embody both Swans?
白天鹅，和黑天鹅
The White, and the Black.
我刚才用手拍过的演员：
All the soloists I tapped:
下午照常彩排
Go to your scheduled rehearsals this afternoon.
而我没拍过的女演员：
And the girls I didn't tap:
下午5点到主角排练室见我
Meet me in the principals' studio at 5:00.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
好了
All right.
- 继续，刚才是左侧练习吗？ - 是的，老师
- Let's go. Did we do left side? - Yes, mistress.
该死！该死！
Fuck! Fuck!
看什么？
What?
如果只是选白天鹅，你是不二人选
If I was only casting the White Swan, she'd be yours.
可现在不是
But I'm not.
音乐老师，奥黛儿之终篇，谢谢
Maestro, Odile's coda, please.
让我看看你的黑天鹅，尼娜
Now show me your Black Swan, Nina.
放开，诱惑我们
Not so controlled. Seduce us.
不仅要诱惑王子，还有在场的人、观众、整个世界
Not just the Prince, but the court, the audience, the entire world.
加油，要像一只结网的蜘蛛
Come on, like a spider spinning a web.
强一点！强一点！加油！
Attack it, attack it! Come on!
- 大驾光临 - 对不起…
- Good of you to join us. - Sorry...
姑娘们，这位是莉莉
Girls, this is Lily.
她从旧金山来，填补丽贝卡的位子
Straight off the plane from San Francisco. She's filling Rebecca's old spot.
去热热身
- Hey. - Get warmed up.
不用，没关系
No, it's okay.
不用热身
I'm good.
需要我再来一次吗？
Should I go again?
不用，谢谢你，尼娜，够了
No, thanks, Nina. I've seen enough.
维罗妮卡，白天鹅变奏曲
Veronica, the White Swan variation.
快点，快点，快点
Come on, come on, come on, please.
好了，音乐老师
All right, Maestro.
二、三…
Two, three...
面试怎么样？
So how'd it go?
你回来晚了，我给办公室的苏茜打了电话
You were late, so I called Susie in the office.
面试！真不敢相信，他让你面试主角
An audition! I can't believe he just sprang that on you.
怎么样？
So?
还好
It was fine.
还好？
Just fine?
小宝贝…
Oh, sweetheart...
别急，慢慢说
You tell me about it.
尼娜，没事吧？
Nina, everything all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
快好了
Almost done.
你练得太猛了
You're working yourself too hard.
- 我们都有不在状态的时候 - 那个女孩，突然闯了进来
- We all have off days. - That girl, um, barged in.
我相信她不是有意的
I'm sure she didn't mean to.
你刚跳舞那会，如果我不领着你去教室，你一定迷路
For a starter, if I hadn't taken you to each of your classes, you'd have been completely lost.
明天我去找他，我要告诉他，我做到了
I'm going to talk to him tomorrow. I'm going to tell him I finished it.
没必要撒谎
You don't need to lie.
他不会相信的
You won't convince him one way or the other.
宝贝
Oh, sweetheart.
我知道这让你很沮丧
I know it's disappointing.
年纪一大，种种压力…
When you start getting older, there's all this
如影随形，我太了解啦
ridiculous pressure. God knows I understand.
不过，没关系
But it's all right.
不管怎样
No matter what.
你也许会再演猫那个角色
You'll probably get to dance the part of the cat again.
那个角色真不错
That's such a wonderful part.
或者，他会让你演大天鹅
Or maybe he'll make you a big swan.
不管怎样，你都会光彩照人
Either way, you'll shine.
我知道
You know...
一觉醒来，一切会变得更美好
Everything will be better in the morning.
一定会的
It always is.
乖女儿
Sweet girl.
有事吗？尼娜
Yes, Nina?
你现在有空吗？
Do you have a minute?
- 我知道你很忙 - 不，时间正合适
- Now's not a good time. I get it. - Now is perfect.
我想告诉你
I just wanted to tell you that
昨晚，我又练了一次终篇
I practiced the coda last night and
我完成了
I finished.
我想让你知道
I thought you should know.
尼娜，听着，老实说我关心的不是你的技巧
Okay, Nina, listen. Honestly, I don't care about your technique.
- 这一点你要明白 - 可昨天…
- You should know that by now. - Yeah, but yesterday...
别说了，还有…
No. Anyway...
我已经选了维罗妮卡，抱歉
I've already chosen Veronica. Sorry.
抱歉
Sorry.
明白了，谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
放弃了？
That's it?
不试一试说服我，让我改变心意吗？
You're not going to try and change my mind?
我也许真得会改变心意
You must have thought it was possible.
不然，干嘛打扮的这么漂亮到这来？
Otherwise, what are you doing here all dolled up?
我想要这个角色
I came to ask for the part.
老实说…
The truth is...
我一直认为，你很适合白天鹅
When I look at you, all I see is the White Swan.
你美丽，怯懦，娇柔
Yes, you're beautiful, fearful, fragile.
演白天鹅最合适
Ideal casting.
可黑天鹅怎么办？一人饰两角，很难的
But the Black Swan? It's a hard fucking job to dance both.
黑天鹅我也能跳
I can dance the Black Swan, too.
真的吗？
Really?
这四年来，你每一次跳黑天鹅…
In four years, every time you dance,
关心地总是每个动作的完美，但我却从没看见过你的激情
I see obsess getting each and every move perfectly right, but I never see you lose yourself.
从没见过，为什么会这样？
Ever. All that discipline for what?
- 我想要完美 - 什么？
- I just want to be perfect. - You what?
我想要完美
I want to be perfect.
完美不是控制出来
Perfection is not just about control.
是爆发出来的
It's also about letting go.
超越自我，征服自己，征服观众
Surprise yourself so you can surprise the audience. Transcendence.
能做到的人不多
And very few have it in them.
我认为我能做到
I think I do have it in me.
你咬我？
You bit me?
你居然咬我！
I can't believe you bit me!
对不起
I'm sorry.
老天，真他妈疼！
Man, that fucking hurt!
看什么？
What?
她为什么总盯着我？
Why's she always staring at me?
结果出来了
Hey, it's been posted.
Hey, it's up!
维罗妮卡
Veronica.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
为什么胡说八道？
Why would you say that?
耍我吗？
Your idea of some sick joke?
你说什么？
What?
去死吧
Fuck you.
尼娜！
Hey, Nina!
恭喜！
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
你好漂亮
You're so beautiful.
恭喜！
Congratulations.
喂？
- Hello? - Hi.
怎么了，有麻烦？
What is it? What's wrong?
我很好
I'm fine.
他选了我，妈妈
He picked me, Mom.
你能听见吗？
Do you hear me?
- 跳天鹅湖？ - 我要跳天鹅女王啦！
- For Swan Lake? - I'm going to be Swan Queen!
妈妈！
Mom!
我一会就回来，想提前让你知道
I'll be home soon. I just wanted to let you know.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
妈妈？
Mom?
妈妈，你在你房间吗？
Mom, are you in your room?
尼娜？
Nina?
你在家吗？
Are you home?
尼娜，我在厨房等你
Nina, when you get out I'm in the kitchen.
快来，宝贝
Come on, sweetie.
我的女儿，天鹅女王
My daughter, the Swan Queen.
我们的最爱，香草蓝莓馅蛋糕
It's our favorite. Vanilla with strawberry filling.
妈妈，别切太大
Oh, Mom, not too big.
太多了…
Oh, that's way, way too much.
- 我们在庆祝，就吃这一次 - 妈妈…
- It's a celebration. It's just this once. - Mom...
我的胃不舒服
My stomach's still in knots.
好
Fine.
倒了！
Then it's garbage!
不要，妈妈，不要，对不起
No, Mom, don't. I'm sorry.
我太为你骄傲了
I'm just... I'm just so proud of you.
看起来真好吃
It looks so yummy.
好，好
Okay, okay.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢你，尼娜
Thank you, Nina.
非常好
That's very nice.
Very nice.
我知道白天鹅不成问题
But I knew the White Swan wouldn't be a problem.
你的任务是如何蜕变成邪恶的黑天鹅
The real work will your metamorphosis into her evil twin.
昨天我看见了她的影子
And I know I saw a flash of her yesterday.
再加一把劲
So get ready to give me more of that bite.
非常好
Excellent.
邪恶力量牵扯你，无法逃离，难以抵制
That evil force is pulling you that you can't escape. That's just out of your control.
你的感觉越来越清晰“它在占有我，占有我”
So you sense it, you get aware of it more: "It's taking me, it's taking me."
多一丝绝望
A little bit more desperate.
对，你可以挥高一些，然后放下…
Right, and you can maybe go up a little bit and then come down, and then...
就是这样
That's it.
瞧她的动作
Watch the way she moves.
不精准，却很轻盈
Imprecise, but effortless.
真实无虚
She's not faking it.
非常漂亮！好，漂亮
Gorgeous! Okay, that's beautiful.
从头再来一遍
Let's start again from the beginning.
从现在起，你和贝丝一个化妆间，小心点
You'll room with Beth from now on, so be considerate.
谢谢，苏茜
Thanks, Susie.
这是卢莱先生送给你的
Those are for you, from Mr. Leroy.
真漂亮
They're beautiful.
我一会就来
I'll be back in a second.
失陪一会
Let me come back to you, please.
我们走
Let's go.
准备好让这群狼品头论足了吗？
Ready to be thrown to the wolves?
我们需要钱，保持微笑
We need our cash, so please don't forget to smile.
女士们先生们，请静一静，好吗？
Ladies and gentlemen, please, may I have your attention?
晚上好
Good evening.
我想宣布一件非常重要的事
Let me make this very important announcement.
有一个人的表演曾让各位目眩神迷、情难自禁
You all had had the chance and the privilege to be enchanted, transported,
有时甚至是悲痛欲绝
and even sometimes devastated, by the performances
她是真正的艺术家
of this true artist of our company.
也是我作品灵感的源泉
She's been a crucial inspiration to my work.
她是众舞者的榜样，更是…
A role model to all dancers, and even more than that,
舞台上最值得欣赏的一抹芳姿
a deeply appreciated presence on our stage.
你们都知道我说得是谁
You all know who I am talking about.
女士们先生们，贝丝・麦金泰尔
Ladies and gentlemen, Beth Macintyre.
不过，我们知道
But as we all know,
每个伟大的事业都有结束的一天
every great career has to come to an end.
贝丝将于本季末退出舞台
Beth is retiring at the end of season.
并在“悲剧女神”中作告别演出
She will be giving her farewell performance as Melpomene,
这也是我的第一支芭蕾舞剧
the role she originated in my first ballet.
我的小公主
My little princess,
我们向你致敬，将你深深怀念
we honor you. You will be greatly missed,
永记心间
and never forgotten.
不过，江山代有才人出
But as we bid adieu to one star, we welcome another.
这一季我们将推出新版“天鹅湖”
We're opening our season with my new version of Swan Lake.
领衔主演“天鹅女王”的是这位楚楚动人的尼娜・塞耶斯
Taking the role of our new Swan Queen, the exquisite Nina Sayers.
不久，各位将一睹她的舞姿
You'll soon have the pleasure of seeing her perform,
不过现在，让我们举杯：敬在场的各位，敬贝丝，敬尼娜
but right now, let's please raise a glass: To all of us. To Beth. To Nina.
敬永恒的美
To beauty.
马上就好！
Just a second.
Just a second!
快点！我憋不住了！
Come on! I'm about to burst!
嗨，是你！
Hey, it's you!
我想我们还没正式介绍过
I don't think we ever officially met.
- 我叫莉莉 - 嗨，我叫尼娜
- I'm Lily. - Hi, I'm Nina.
我知道，新的天鹅女王
Yes, our new Swan Queen.
- 帮我拿一下 - 好的
- Here, hold this. - Yeah, sure.
你一定兴奋地要命
You must be so excited.
你紧张吗？
Are you freaking out?
- 是的… - 是吗？
- Yeah... - Yeah?
没关系
Oh, it's okay.
换成是我，一定会晕头转向
Oh, I'd be losing my mind.
我得过去了…
I should get back...
别…别这样，等一会
No, no, no, come on, stay.
陪我一会
Keep me company.
失陪
Excuse me.
你在这，跟我来
Oh, there you are. Come on.
他们恨不得把你吞了，你却飘然在此
Hey. They tried to eat you alive, but here you are.
表现得很好
You did well.
真的？
- Really? - Mm-hmm.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
上西区
Upper west side.
顺道去我家喝一杯
Stop at my place for a drink. It's on the way.
托马斯，过去和凯伦・哈罗维打个招呼
Thomas, you need to say hello to Karen Holloway.
我得去拍个马屁，一会就回来，在这等我，好吗？
A minute more of ass-kissing. I'll be back. Wait for me here, all right?
你好，凯伦！
Hello, Karen!
贝丝！
Beth!
真遗憾，你要离开我们
I'm so sorry to hear you're leaving the company.
你是怎么得到这个角色的？
What did you do to get this role?
他总说你缺乏激情
He always said you were such a frigid little girl.
你怎么让他改变了主意？
What did you do to make him change his mind?
和他上床？
Did you suck his cock?
不是每个人都需要这么做
Not all of us have to.
你个无耻的婊子！
You fucking whore!
你就是个无耻的小婊子！
You're a fucking little whore!
冷静，怎么回事？
Whoa, what's going on here?
我得和你谈谈
Hey, I need to talk to you.
- 你喝醉了，回家吧 - 我得和你谈谈
- You're drunk. You should go home. - I need to talk to you.
不！你敢！你敢就这样踢掉我！
No! Don't you do that! Don't you dismiss me like that!
我的小公主，拜托，冷静一点
My little princess, please. Pull it together.
- 走吧 - 我会去找你的
- Come. - I'm coming by later.
我有件东西送给你，以表我的感激之情
I have something for you. It's a token of my appreciation.
- 好 - 别客气，下手狠点，尼娜
- Right. - You make the most of it, Nina.
别介意，这行就是这样
Don't worry. It's typical.
请坐，我们应该谈谈角色
Please. I thought it'd be good to talk about the role.
冲谈一下拘谨的气氛
Drown this a little.
我们不想彼此有隔阂
I don't want there to be any boundaries between us.
- 我也这么想 - 很好
- No, me neither. - Good.
那么…你有男朋友吗？
So... You got a boyfriend?
没有
No.
过去交的男朋友多吗？
Have you had many in the past?
交过几个
A few.
不过，都不是正式的
But no one serious.
你不会是处女吧？
You're not a virgin are you?
不是
No.
那就用不着害羞
So there's nothing to be embarrassed about.
你喜欢做爱吗？
And you enjoy making love?
什么？
Excuse me?
别大惊小怪，性
Come on, sex.
喜欢吗？
Do you enjoy it?
我们必须谈这个话题
We need to be able to talk about this.
我给你布置一个家庭作业
I've got a little homework assignment for you.
回家后，自慰
Go home and touch yourself.
放松一下
Live a little.
天晚了，明天还有很多工作
Well it's late. Lots of work tomorrow.
门房会为你叫出租车
The doorman will find a cab for you.
听起来今晚很精彩，真希望我也能去
Sounds like quite an evening. I wish I could have been there.
我向他们提过
You know I asked.
我知道，苏茜对我说了
I know you did. Susie told me.
我猜他想和你单独在一起
Guess he wanted you all to himself.
可是为什么？
But why?
我不怪他
Don't blame him.
耳环哪来的？
Where'd you get these?
假的
They're fake.
我以为是真
Fooled me.
我自己能行
I can do it.
他一定整晚都在你身边
He must have been by your side all night.
带着你四处招摇
Showing you off.
- 尼娜… - 疹子而已
- Oh, Nina... - It's just a rash.
疹子？你在说什么？
Rash? What are you talking about?
前几天更严重，现在好多了
It was worse a few days ago. It's fine already.
- 你一定又用手抓了 - 没有
- You've been scratching yourself again. - No I haven't.
妈妈！
Mom!
怎么有这个坏毛病…
This disgusting habit...
老天，我以为你改了这个坏毛病，尼娜
Jesus Christ, I thought you were done with this, Nina.
披肩，从明天起披肩不许离身
Shrugs. You'll keep wearing the shrugs.
坐下，你有一件白色的
Sit down. You have the white one,
还有一件粉色的，应该能遮住
and the pink one. And that'll hide it.
然后，我再找一点那种贵粉底，我们还剩一些
And then I'll dig out that expensive coverup. We still have some.
不会有人发现的
No one will see it.
妈妈，别这样
Mom, please,
因为这个角色，是吗？压力太大
It's the role, isn't it? It's all this pressure.
我就知道你承受不了，我就知道
I knew it'd be too much. I knew it.
你会没事的
You're all right.
You'll be all right.
贝丝进医院了
Beth's in the hospital.
发生了车祸
She had an accident.
不！
Oh no!
贝丝？
Beth?
怎么回事？
What happened?
她冲进马路被车撞了
She walked into the street and got hit by a car.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我敢肯定，她是故意的
I'm almost sure she did it on purpose.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为贝丝做任何事都带着一股黑暗的冲动
Because everything Beth does comes from within, from some dark impulse.
所以她的表演充满着快感
I guess that's what makes her so thrilling to watch.
让人战栗
So dangerous.
某一时刻，甚至完美无缺
Even perfect at times.
但却充满着该死的毁灭性
But also so damned destructive.
是吵架那天发生的吗？
Was it right after we saw her?
等等…这些跟你没关系
Wait, wait, wait. This has nothing to do with you.
和你没有关系，别担心
It's not your problem, so don't let yourself be distracted.
现在你是主角，尼娜
This is your moment, Nina.
好好把握
Don't let it go.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
尼娜？
Nina?
宝贝，我要来喽？
Sweetie, are you ready for me?
加油！
And... Come on!
别控制，尼娜，我要看见激情
Forget about control, Nina. I want to see passion.
加油！
Come on.
伸臂
太僵硬了，没有生气，放松
Stiff like a dead corpse. Let it go.
放松，放松
Let it go. Let it go.
再一次
And again.
感觉你的横隔膜
Feels like you have your diaphragm
有点收缩？
is in a bit of a contraction?
好
I'm okay.
将气吸入我手的方向，吸气
Breathe in to this hand. Breathe in to this hand.
深吸一口气，好
Breathe in, all the way. Good.
呼气
And exhale.
做挺背曲膝的时候，前面是不是有点僵硬？
Does it feel jammed in the front every time you plie?
有时会，不常发生
Sometimes, not always.
- 再拉一次，好吗？ - 好
- One more pull, okay? - Okay.
- 好点吗？ - 是的
- Is that okay? - Yeah.
大卫，能问你一个问题吗？
David, can I ask you a question?
说实话，你会和那样的女孩上床吗？
Honestly, would you fuck that girl?
不会
No.
没人会
No one would.
尼娜
Nina...
你的舞蹈缺乏激情
Your dancing is just as frigid...
该死！
Fuck!
我们还在工作，请把灯打开！
We're still working here, please. Lights!
开灯！
The lights!
谢谢！
Thank you!
各位，你们可以走了，谢谢
Okay, guys, you can go. Thanks for your patience.
不是你，你留下
No, no, you stay. You stay.
你们好好玩
Have fun, you two.
好
Okay.
到这来
Come here.
过来，过来…
Come, come, come, come.
我来演王子
I'll be the Prince.
别控制，别控制
Let it go. Let it go.
感觉我的抚摸
Feel my touch.
迎合我
Respond to it.
快
Come on.
张开嘴，张开，张开
Open your mouth. Open it. Open up.
现在是我在引诱你
That was me seducing you,
应该你引诱我
when it needs to be the other way around.
等等…
Please...
谁在那？
Who is that?
你没事吧？
You okay?
你不能在这吸烟
You can't smoke in here.
你知我知…
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
大日子越来越近，是不是？
The big day's getting closer and closer, huh?
我已经等不及了，相信你的表演会很精彩
Well, I can't wait. I think you're going to be amazing.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么…
So...
你想谈谈吗？
Do  you want to talk about it?
不知怎么说
It's that hard to.
卢莱对你太凶是吗？
Leroy playing a little too rough for you?
没事的，尼娜，他是个混蛋
Come on, Nina. He's a prick.
他很了不起
He's brilliant.
没错，可他也很凶
Sure, but it's not like he's all warm and fuzzy.
你不了解他…
What you don't know is...
有人暗恋老师！
Someone's hot for teacher!
别激动，没事，很正常
Oh, come on, it's okay. I don't blame you.
我要回家了
I should go home.
尼娜，别这样，我开玩笑的
Nina, come on. I'm just playing around.
尼娜！
Nina!
宝贝？你在里面干什么？
Sweetie? What are you doing in there?
再来
Again.
到底什么问题？
Do you have any corrections?
莉莉告诉我，看见你在哭
Lily told me that she saw you crying.
心情很不好
That you were very upset
让我对你温和一点
and that I should take it easy on you.
不是我让她说的
I didn't tell her that.
也许你该休息一下
Maybe you need a little break.
休息一、两天，或者一个月，你觉得呢？
A day or two. Or maybe a month. What do you think?
她不该乱说话
She shouldn't have said anything.
不，是你不该发牢骚
No, you shouldn't be whining in the first place.
我没有
I didn't.
你本该更优秀
You could be brilliant.
可你是个胆小鬼
But you're a coward.
对不起
Sorry.
别再说这句话！这就是你的问题
No, stop saying that! That's exactly what I'm talking about.
别再软弱下去
Stop being so fucking weak.
再来！
Again!
莉莉…
Lily...
瞧瞧，是谁大架光临了
Oh, look who's decided to grace us with her presence.
我要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
好
Okay.
马上
Now.
闭嘴
Shut up.
来吧
Come on.
什么事？
What's up?
你和托马斯说了昨晚的事？
You told Thomas about last night?
是啊，早上我碰见他，他说你们遇到了问题
Oh, yeah. I ran into him in the morning and he said you guys were having some trouble.
他为什么要和你说这些？
Why would he talk to you?
你说什么，陛下
Oh, excuse me, your highness.
我告诉他你很努力，我相信你会很棒的
I just told him you're working your ass off and I think you'll be great.
你不该说
Well you shouldn't have.
好
Okay.
他对你毛手毛脚吗？
Has he tried anything with you?
他可是恶名在外
He has a reputation.
我有理由担心，尼娜，你每天回来的很晚
I have a right to be concerned, Nina. You've been staying late so many nights.
彩排，我希望他别占你便宜，就担心这事
Rehearsing. I just hope he isn't taking advantage, that's all.
他没有
He's not.
很好
Good.
我不想你走我的老路
I just don't want you to make the same mistake I did.
谢谢
Thanks.
不是因为你
Not like that.
别像我一样，毁了事业
I just mean as far as my career was concerned.
你什么事业？
What career?
因为生你放弃的事业
The one I gave up to have you.
我28了
I'm twenty-eight.
接着说？
So?
仅仅…
Only that...
仅仅什么？
Only what?
没什么
Nothing.
- 什么？ - 没什么
- What? - Nothing.
你皮肤怎么样？
How is your skin?
很好
Fine.
还抓没抓？
- Are you leaving it alone? - Mm-hmm.
让我看看
Let me see.
- 脱掉衬衣 - 不
- Take off your shirt. - No.
有事吗？
Can I help you?
是谁？
Who was that?
没人
It was no one.
有谁？
Hello?
怎么是你？
What are you doing here?
我是来道歉的
I just came by to apologize.
你说的对，我不该和他谈你的事
You're right. I should have never spoken to him about you.
- 宝贝 - 等一会
- Sweetheart. - Give me a second.
- 吃晚饭… - 妈妈，拜托
- Your dinner... - Mom, please.
她可真难缠
Oh, she's a trip.
你怎么知道我住哪？
How do you know where I live?
山人自有妙计
I have my ways.
老天，别紧张，办公室的苏茜告诉我的
Jesus, relax. I got it from Susie in the office.
这件事让我很不舒服，我真的想弥补一下
Look, I feel really shitty about what I did, and I really want to make it up to you.
我请你出去吃饭怎么样？
So how about I take you out to dinner?
- 我不知道… - 好吧，没关系
- I don't think... - Okay, that's fine.
喝一杯呢？
What about drinks?
宝贝，你该休息了
Sweetie, you need to rest.
- 老天 - 等等
- Jesus. - Wait.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
出去
I'm going out.
什么？尼娜！
What? Nina!
你明天要上台
You're on the stage tomorrow.
他居然那么叫她
I can't believe he calls her that.
- 真恶心 - 我倒觉得很贴心
- It's so gross. - I think it's sweet.
小公主？
Little Princess?
- 他可能对每个女孩都这么叫 - 不可能
- He probably calls every girl that. - No way.
只对贝丝
That's just for Beth.
我打赌，过几天他就会叫你小公主
Well, I bet he'll be calling you Little Princess any day now.
我不知道
I don't know about that.
他会的，上床的时候可别饶了他
Oh, sure he will. Just got to let him lick your pussy.
干酪汉堡包，大份番茄酱
Cheeseburger, extra bloody.
非常感谢
Mmm, dankesche.
酱不够可以叫我
Let me know if that's juicy enough for you.
我会的
Oh, I will.
干酪够吗？
You have enough cheese?
你可多的很（意思是你很烦）
No, but you do.
慢用
Enjoy.
来
All right.
想打扮打扮吗？
Wanna spruce up?
干嘛，我带着备用
What, I carry a spare
以防玩过头
in case I wake up somewhere unexpected.
他怎么样？
So how is he?
托马斯
Thomas.
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
- 少来 - 我真的不想谈他
- Oh, come on. - I really don't want to talk about that.
好吧
Okay.
你真得放松放松
You really need to relax.
一颗给你
One for you,
一颗给我
one for me.
别担心，货很纯，我保证是从旧金山带过来的
Oh, and don't worry. It's pure, I promise. I brought it with me straight from San Francisco.
这是什么？
What is it?
开玩笑？
Are you kidding?
你从没嗑过药？
You've never rolled?
别担心，它能帮你放松下来
Oh, relax. Here. It'll loosen you up.
你会看见无垠的夜空
Wait till you see the night sky.
药力会持续多久？
How long does it last?
最多，几个小时
A couple hours, tops.
不用了
It's okay.
好吧
Okay.
尼娜！
Nina, hi!
我们有伴了，这是汤姆，这是杰瑞
I thought we could use some company. So this is Tom and this is Jerry.
- 实际上，我叫安德鲁 - 汤姆
- Actually it's Andrew. - Tom.
- 我得走了… - 不行，不能走，我刚点了酒
- I have to go... - Oh, no you can't go. I just got us some drinks.
我不应该…
I shouldn't...
我们明天要上台
We're on the stage tomorrow.
去哪？回家找妈妈？
So what are you going to do? Go home to Mommy?
来吧，玩一会
Come on, live a little.
药力只有几个小时，是吗？
It's just a couple hours, right?
是的
Tops.
干杯
Cheers.
你还没告诉我你是谁
You haven't told me who you are.
我是个舞蹈演员
I'm a dancer.
不是这意思，你的名字
No, I mean your name.
- 尼娜 - 你俩是姐妹？
- Oh. Nina. - So are you two sisters?
- 是的 - 不是
- Yes. - No.
- 闺中姐妹 - 我们在同一个团跳舞
- Blood sisters. - We dance in the same company.
芭蕾舞女演员，难怪你们长的这么像
Ah, ballerinas. No wonder you two look alike.
我也看出来了，你俩是同志小情人
I see now. Tom and Jerry here are gay lovers.
- 真幽默 - 我喜欢自娱自乐
- Very funny. - I like to amuse myself.
我从来没接触过芭蕾
I've never been to the ballet.
这么看，你绝对不是同志
Then you are definitely not gay.
我是说，芭蕾有点枯燥，是不是？
I mean, it's kind of boring, isn't it?
- 老实说 - 不，不是这样
- Be honest. - No it's not.
这么说吧，不是每个人都能接受
You know what? It's just not for everyone.
找个时间过来看看，我给你们赠
You should come sometime. I can comp you tickets whenever you want.
好，好
Yeah. Yeah.
- 那真是太棒了，谢谢 - 好了…
- Yeah, that would be neat. Thanks. - Okay well...
我们再喝一杯
I think it's time for another round.
干杯
Bottoms up.
你们在排什么戏？
So what are you guys working on now?
不好意思
Sorry.
天鹅湖
Swan Lake.
是吗？
Yeah?
你看过？
You know it?
没有
No, not really.
听说过
Heard of it.
说的什么？
What's it about?
是说一个女孩被人变成了天鹅
It's about a girl who gets turned into a swan,
她需要爱的力量打破诅咒
and she needs love to break the spell.
可她的王子却爱上了不该爱的人
But her prince falls for the wrong girl,
于是她自杀了
and so she kills herself.
是个悲剧
It's not a happy ending then.
实际上，很美
It's beautiful, actually.
像你一样
Like you.
什么？
Huh?
我说你很美
I said you're beautiful.
很好笑？
That's funny?
某人的情绪上来喽
Looks like someone might be rolling.
好了，过来，去跳舞
All right, come on. Come on, it's time to go dance.
尼娜！
Nina!
搞什么？你去哪？
Hey, what the fuck? Where you going?
尼娜！
Nina!
你去哪？
Where are you going?
你知道现在几点了吗？
Do you have any idea what time it is?
很晚了？
Late?
你去了哪？
Where have you been?
到月亮上去了
To the moon and back.
- 你喝酒了 - 猜 对 啦！
- You've been drinking. - Ding ding ding ding ding!
还有什么？
- What else? - Hmm?
你还做了什么？
What else have you been doing?
原来你想知道他们的名字？
Oh, you want to know their names?
- 快去睡觉 - 是两个人，汤姆和杰瑞
- You need to sleep this off. - There were two. Tom and Jerry.
- 闭嘴，尼娜 - 我和他们都上了床
- Be quiet, Nina. - And I fucked them both.
闭嘴！
Shut your mouth!
- 不许进来 - 你干什么？
- Don't come in here. - What's this?
懂不懂什么叫隐私，我不再是小女孩了
It's called privacy. I'm not twelve anymore.
- 你现在脑子不清楚 - 走开！
- You're not my Nina right now... - Leave me alone!
小甜心
Sweat girl.
为什么不叫醒我？
Why didn't you wake me up?
我要搬出去
I'm moving out.
是我的曲子！
My music!
托马斯，真对不起
Thomas, I am so sorry.
继续跳
Keep on going.
去热身
Go get warmed up.
很好
That was good.
非常之好
Actually, really good.
好，休息十分钟
Okay, let's take ten.
他只是让我示范一下，明白吗？
Look, he just wanted to mark it and asked me to step up, okay?
我睡过了头
I overslept.
惨喽，不过你玩很开心，对吗？
Oops. But hey, at least you had a good time, right?
你在我酒里下了东西
You put something in my drink.
没错
Yeah.
早上却一个人先走了
And then you just took off in the morning.
早上？
In the morning?
你在我家过的夜
Yeah, you slept over.
没有
Um, no.
除非你叫汤姆，还长了一根老二
Unless your name's Tom and you had a dick.
我们…
我们怎么了，尼娜？
What, Nina?
是不是在梦里和我上床了？
Did you have some sort of lesbian wet dream about me?
- 别说了 - 老天！
- Stop. - Oh my God!
老天，是真的！我成了你的性幻想对象！
Oh my God, you did! You fantasized about me!
- 闭嘴！ - 我床上功夫好吗？
- Shut up! - Was I good?
最后一幕
The final act.
你的最后一场戏
You're trying to dance.
梦想几乎成真！如此真实！
You've tasted your dream! Touched it!
可却被砸得粉碎！
Only to have it crushed!
你的心破碎了！
Your heart is broken,
受伤了，你的生命在枯萎
wounded. Your life force fading.
鲜血滴滴下坠
The blood drips.
黑天鹅偷走了你的爱人，只有一条路可以熄灭痛苦
The Black Swan stole your love. There is only one way to end the pain.
你不再恐惧，接受了命运的安排
You are not fearful, but filled with acceptance.
你垂目看了看罗斯巴
And you look down at Rothbart,
又看了看王子
and then at the Prince,
之后，对，注视观众
and then, yes, at the audience.
然后，纵身跃下
And then you jump.
快点，跳，没事的，跳！
Go ahead. Jump. Jump!
好了，大家去喝杯水，然后做分段练习
Okay, everybody get a drink of water, then it's notes.
你瘦了
You lost weight.
请脱下披肩
Take off your shrug, please.
很好
Very good.
向前看，快好了
Face front. We're almost done.
完成，好了
And that's it. Okay.
好了，非常感谢
We're done. Thank you very much.
乔治娜，我叫莉莉，托马斯让我来…
Georgina, I'm Lily. Thomas sent me...
我知道，给你也做一身天鹅女王的服装
Yes, we have to get you measured for the Swan Queen costumes.
她怎么在这？
What's she doing here?
他让我做你的替补
He made me your alternate.
只是以防万一
Look, it's just in case.
托马斯，托马斯
Thomas. Thomas.
- 托马斯 - 什么事？
- Thomas. - Yes?
不可以用她
It can't be her.
你先去，我一会来
Okay, why don't you just go. I'll catch up later.
怎么了？
What's going on?
莉莉...你让她做我的替补？
Lily... You made her my alternate?
这是惯例，莉莉是最佳人选
There's always an alternate. Lily is the best choice.
不，她想顶掉我
No, she wants my role.
每个人都想顶掉你
Every dancer in the world wants your role.
不，这不一样，她别有用心
No, this is different. She is after me.
- 她想取代我 - 没有人别有用心
- She is trying to replace me. - Nobody is after you.
不，请相信我…
- No, please believe me...
我知道你压力很大，不过，你早上的表演很有突破
I know it's been a struggle. But you just had a breakthrough this morning.
明天是属于你的，演一出好戏，谁也不用想
Tomorrow is yours. Just give a great performance and you won't have to worry about Lily or anybody else.
现在回家，好好休息
Now go home and rest.
从“幻梦”再来一次
From the vision again.
怎么回事？
What happened?
我有我的生活，别太拼了，明天是大日子
I've got a life.don't work too hard. It's a big day tomorrow.
我还在工作
I'm still working in here.
请把灯打开好吗？
Could you please turn the lights back on?
有人吗？
Hello?
你来干什么？
What are you doing here?
对不起
I'm so sorry.
现在我才了解那种感受，她想取代我
I know how it feels now. She's trying to replace me.
我该怎么办？
What do I do?
你偷我东西？
You stole my things?
我想完美，像你一样
I was just trying to be perfect, like you.
完美？
Perfect?
我一点也不完美
I'm not perfect.
我什么都不是
I'm nothing.
什么都不是！
Nothing!
不是！不是！
Nothing, nothing!
乖女儿
Sweet girl.
妈妈？
Mommy?
乖女儿，乖女儿
Sweet girl. Sweet girl.
闭嘴！
Stop!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
宝贝？
Sweetie?
尼娜？
Nina?
尼娜！
Nina!
走开！
Go away!
开门！
Open the door!
走开！
Go away!
开门！尼娜！
Open the door, Nina!
尼娜！
Nina!
出去！
Get out!
- 你到底怎么了？ - 出去！
- What's wrong with you? - Get out!
- 出去！ - 你看见什么了？
- Get out! - What do you see?
出去！
Get out!
没事了
It's okay.
妈在这
I'm here.
你整晚都在抓
You were scratching all night.
我的闹钟呢？
Where's my clock?
- 别管了 - 几点了？
- Don't worry about that. - What time is it?
- 今晚演出，我必须… - 不行，不行…
- The show is tonight, I have to... - No, no, no, no.
别担心
Don't worry.
我给剧院打了电话，告诉他们你不舒服
I called the theater and I told them you aren't feeling well.
我一定得去！
I have to go!
- 不行，不行，不能去 - 放开我
- No. No, you don't. - Let go of me.
你身子不好，不能离开
You're staying in here until you feel better.
门把手呢？
Where is it?
这个角色会毁了你
This role is destroying you.
- 过去！过去！ - 尼娜…！
- Move. Move! - Nina...!
- 我的乖女儿到底怎么了？ - 她死了！
- What happened to my sweet girl? - She's gone!
尼娜！尼娜！
Nina! Oh, Nina!
不，求你！
No, please!
- 你生病了！ - 放开我！
- You're not well! - Let go of me!
你承受不了
You can't handle this.
我承受不了？
I can't?
我是天鹅女王，而你只能一辈子跑龙套
I'm the Swan Queen. You're the one who never left the corps.
尼娜！
Nina!
你来干什么？
What are you doing here?
尼娜？
Nina?
她不是病了吗？
She was supposed to be sick.
等等，我和她谈一会
Give us a minute.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我很好
I'm fine.
尼娜
Nina.
干什么？
What?
我已经让莉莉上了
I've already asked Lily.
你正式宣布了吗？
Have you announced it?
经过贝丝那件事，你还想制造新话题吗？
After Beth, do you really need another controversy?
我来了，托马斯
I'm here, Thomas.
我来演
I'm doing it.
你的本性在障碍你
The only person standing in your way is you.
赶走它，释放你自己
It's time to let it go. Lose yourself.
白天鹅，十分钟后上场
White Swan, up in ten.
你在干什么？该你上台了
What are you doing? You need to be upstage.
你演得真差
You suck.
尼娜
Okay, Nina.
搞什么？
What the fuck?
- 你没事吧？ - 尼娜，你没事吧？
- Are you okay? - Nina, are you okay?
你说，到底他妈怎么回事？
Can you tell me what the fuck happened?
- 不是我的错，是他失的手 - 真他妈失败
- It wasn't my fault. He dropped me. - This is a fucking disaster.
开局不顺吧？一定丢死人了
Rough start, huh? Must have been pretty humiliating.
滚出我的房间
Get out of my room.
我真为下一场捏一把汗
I'm worried about the next act.
我觉得你心有余而力不足
I'm just not sure you're feeling up to it.
别说了，快别说了
Stop. Please stop.
黑天鹅还是让我跳吧？
How about I dance the Black Swan for you?
走开！
Leave me alone!
该我了！
My turn!
It's my turn!
黑天鹅，五分钟后上场
Black Swan, places in five.
快过来
Come on.
跳得漂亮，十五分钟以后，最后一幕
Good job. Fifteen to the last act.
嘿，你真绝了
Hey. You were amazing.
说真的，我知道我们之间有点小误会
Seriously, I know that things got a little messed up between us,
但是，老天，我服你了！
but I mean, holy shit, you completely blew me away!
好了，不说了
Okay, well I guess that's it.
不妨碍你了，再见
So I'll let you finish. Bye.
听见观众的欢呼吗？
Can you hear them?
他们爱你！他们爱你！
They love you!
我的小公主，我就知道你有那股魔力
My little princess, I always knew you had it in you.
来，我们一起出去
Come on. Let's take you out.
快去叫人！
Go get some help.
Go get some help!
你都干了什么？
What did you do?
- 我感觉到了 - 什么？
- I felt it. - What?
完美
I felt perfect.
我完美了
I was perfect.
尼娜！尼娜！尼娜！
Nina! Nina! Nina!
谢谢观赏 TLF中文字幕站